Guide to the the Douglas "Swede" Dennis Collection M1843
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
The Douglas "Swede" Dennis Collection
1988-2009
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Padgett, Abigail
M1843
3.5 Linear Feet: 7 manuscript boxes
Correspondence between Angola inmate Douglas Dennis and others, especially attorney and prison reform advocate Robert Perske.
Access to Collection
Open for research. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by Stanford University, Special Collections in 2011.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence between Angola inmate Douglas Dennis and attorney and prison reform advocate Robert Perske from 1993 until Dennis' death in 2009. Douglas B. "Swede" Dennis, who was born in Chicago in 1935, was arrested for vagrancy while hitchhiking in Louisiana in 1957. In an altercation at the Shreveport City Jail he killed his cellmate and was sentenced to the notorious Louisiana State Penitentiary at Angola. Dennis killed another inmate there and received a second life sentence, but escaped and lived as as a fugitive for ten years. Upon his capture he was sent back to Angola, and becamer a reporter for The Angolite, the prison magazine. Towards the end of his life he sought a pardon due to old age and health issues, but was denied. Also included are letters to and from San Diego author Abigail Padgett, who knew Dennis for 18 years, and Arnold Schrank.
Prisons -- Louisiana -- Angola; Prison reform; Perske, Robert; Crane, Richard; Dennis, Douglas; Schrank, Arnold; Padgett, Abigail; Padgett, Abigail; Louisiana State Penitentiary
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - Douglas Dennis to Abigail Padgett, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Douglas Dennis to Richard Crane, 1990-2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Douglas Dennis to Abigail Padgett, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Douglas Dennis to Abigail Padgett, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Douglas Dennis to Abigail Padgett, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Douglas Dennis to Abigail Padgett, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Douglas Dennis to Abigail Padgett, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Douglas Dennis to Abigail Padgett, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Douglas Dennis to Abigail Padgett, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Robert Perske and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Robert Perske and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Robert Perske and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Robert Perske and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Robert Perske and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Robert Perske and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Robert Perske and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Robert Perske and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Robert Perske and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Robert Perske and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Robert Perske and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, January 3, 2000 - September 21, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, September 25, 2000 - December 30, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, January 3, 2001 - April 8, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, April 13, 2001- July 24, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, July 29, 2001 - October 22, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, October 23, 2001 - December 31, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, February 24, 2002 - April 27, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, May 2, 2002 - July 19, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, January 2, 2002 - August 22, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, July 21, 2002 - November 1, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, November 5, 2002 - December 29, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, January 4, 2004 - April 30, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, May 6, 2004 - December 29, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, January 3, 2005 - August 16, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, February 19, 2003 - May 26, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, January 1, 2003 - February 13, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, October 30, 2003 - December 31, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, August 17, 2005 - December 27, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, January 5, 2006 - May 23, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, May 28, 2006 - December 30, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, January 1, 2007 - July 21, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, July 23, 2007 - December 31, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, January 2008 - December 2008 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Arnold Schrank and Douglas Dennis Correspondence, January 4, 2009 - May 26, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Series 2: Ephemera and Printed Matter
  - Description of Collection Written by Robert Perske (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Ephemera (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Arnold Schrank Ephemera and Photographs (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - The Angolite 20, no. 1-5 (1995) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Angolite 20, no. 6 (1995) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Angolite 21, no. 2-5 (1996) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Saint Louis University Public Law Review XIV, no. 1 (1994) With Article by Douglas Dennis (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Court Documents Regarding Douglas Dennis (Box 3, Folder 10)